<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding, Cooking and Random Things (Posts about english)</title><link>https://nix1.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://nix1.github.io/categories/english.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 10:27:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Is Semantic UI suitable for your project?</title><link>https://nix1.github.io/posts/is-semantic-ui-suitable-for-your-project/</link><dc:creator>Paweł Sierszeń</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than a year ago, we decided to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://semantic-ui.com/"&gt;Semantic UI&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://codility.com/"&gt;Codility&lt;/a&gt; as the framework that will help us build nice user interfaces faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/semantic-ui.png" class="align-right" src="https://nix1.github.io/images/semantic-ui.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, we often had to discover how to do things Semantic-way, but perhaps it also applies to any other framework. Switching from what we had previously was a bit difficult, but we were happy with the outcome, as having a library such as this one saves a lot of time both in the UX team and in the dev team. In particular, moving the definition of how things look to HTML (via a large number of CSS classes) versus writing large amounts of CSS is certainly much more maintainable and it's a big deal in the large code base such as ours. If you are starting a new project you won't have the problems with conversion that we had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things that we changed in the configuration is the number of grid columns, which was 16 by default. 12 columns are certainly a much better choice, because they give you much more freedom - there were things we just couldn't implement with the default value, like for instance the responsive footer that has 6 segments. I would highly recommend switching to 12 columns before you start working with grids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="/images/semantic-ui2.png" class="align-center" src="https://nix1.github.io/images/semantic-ui2.png"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can use any of the standard themes it will be certainly easier than customizing it; however, it seems that designers always want to change something :) Customizations are usually added to special files in your theme (namely, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;theme.variables&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;theme.overrides&lt;/tt&gt;) and after any change you have to recompile Semantic; this doesn't fit very well into out development cycle, because we didn't want to add it as yet another step that happens during the deployment (or even local server run), so we ended up committing the compiled sources into our repository. Fortunately, now we don't need to modify it very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a relatively young library so sometimes you can run into bugs (mostly with behaviour implemented in JS, the CSS part rather works well) or things which are not very well documented. This was the most painful when we were trying to develop Semantic-based things in React. Basically, we've found out that trying to synchronise the UI with internal React/Redux states is not a good option. However, since then, the Semantic-UI-React official library was created which is really awesome and totally jQuery-free (we would love to get rid of jQuery in the long run), although some features like animations are not yet implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one bad thing about the CSS, sometimes (but probably rarely) you will want to override some styles and then you won't get away without long selectors and even &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;!important&lt;/tt&gt;. However, over time we learned that it's not as bad as it looks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative that we considered was using Bootstrap. The main reason was that with Bootstrap we would look like half of the Internet so we wanted something that looks nicer. Although sometimes we regretted not choosing it, for now we are definitely sticking to Semantic, in particular now when Semantic-UI-React is available, actively developed and we are doing more and more things in React/Redux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>codility</category><category>english</category><guid>https://nix1.github.io/posts/is-semantic-ui-suitable-for-your-project/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 08:27:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Polyphasic Sleep Schedules – some mathematics</title><link>https://nix1.github.io/posts/polyphasic-sleep-schedules-some-mathematics/</link><dc:creator>Paweł Sierszeń</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first post not related to web development, I’d like to present some calculations
on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyphasic_sleep"&gt;polyphasic sleep&lt;/a&gt; which I’ve made for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have no idea what I’m talking about, you’d better read some introduction first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic formula behind most of the polyphasic sleep patterns is that a 20-min nap is roughly
equivalent to 1.5 hour of “normal” sleep. Based on the data
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.dustincurtis.com/sleep.html"&gt;presented by Dustin Curtis&lt;/a&gt;, we have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="29%"&gt;
&lt;col width="27%"&gt;
&lt;col width="23%"&gt;
&lt;col width="21%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Waste (monophasic)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Siesta (biphasic)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.3 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 2-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.2 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 3-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 4-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.5 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.8 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Uberman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.33 h (20 mins)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t understand why in the article written by Dustin Curtis the 4-nap Everyman is
defined as four or five naps plus 1.5 h core sleep. The 5-nap Everyman is the same as
Uberman, and the 1.5 h core sleep seems to be a waste of time.
You may be surprised that I’ve included Uberman as 20-min core sleep plus five 20-min naps,
not as six naps. The reason for that is that I wanted to have some continuity when counting naps :)
.. Let’s make a graph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the relation between the number of naps and the total amount of sleep is &lt;strong&gt;not linear&lt;/strong&gt;.
So &lt;strong&gt;the benefit of going from Monophasic to Biphasic is bigger than going from the 4-nap
Everyman to Uberman&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col width="28%"&gt;
&lt;col width="20%"&gt;
&lt;col width="21%"&gt;
&lt;col width="31%"&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Waste (monophasic)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;–&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Siesta (biphasic)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17.7 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.4%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.4%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 2-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18.8 h&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17.7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 3-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.2%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Everyman 4-nap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21.2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32.3%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Uberman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.9%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;strong&gt;it doesn’t really matter how much less you sleep, it matters how much more time
you have and how much more you can get done&lt;/strong&gt;. Keeping in mind that each additional nap
introduces significant disturbance into one’s lifestyle and scheduling, I believe that &lt;strong&gt;there
must be some optimum in beetween&lt;/strong&gt;. My theory seem to be supported by the fact that the longest
running Uberman sleepers I know about, that is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.puredoxyk.com/index.php/polyphasic-sleep-portal/"&gt;PureDoxyk&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2005/10/polyphasic-sleep/"&gt;Steve Pavlina&lt;/a&gt; have both switched
to Everyman-3. On the other end of the spectrum, we have whole societies that use the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Siesta"&gt;1-nap biphasic
Siesta sleeping pattern&lt;/a&gt; (I lived in Italy for some time and
I think that the siesta is great!), so it must have been really worth the trouble, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>english</category><guid>https://nix1.github.io/posts/polyphasic-sleep-schedules-some-mathematics/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:18:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Easy Pizza – The Simplest (No-Knead) Home‑Made Pizza Ever</title><link>https://nix1.github.io/posts/easy-pizza-the-simplest-no-knead-home-made-pizza-ever/</link><dc:creator>Paweł Sierszeń</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recipe is highly inspired by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cookingforgeeks.com/"&gt;Cooking for Geeks&lt;/a&gt;
– most importantly, the proportions are taken from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;170 g (6 oz / 1⅓ cup) flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 g (0.2 oz / 1 teaspoon) table salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 g (0.7 oz) compressed yeast or 10 g (0.35 oz / 1 tablespoon) instant yeast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;120 g (4.23 oz / ½ cup) warm water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have all the ingredients…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a bowl, mix salt with flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add instant yeast to flour or dissolve compressed yeast in water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the liquid/water into the bowl and quickly mix using a spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re done, just cover it and leave it alone for 4 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dough will be a bit sticky, so sprinkle it with flour. Shaping is probably the easiest using
a rolling pin on non-stick paper. It takes some practice to get a nice shape, so don’t put too
much attention to the shape, just try to make it as flat as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preheat your oven to the highest temperature available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Hint: You can put some water in a metal cup or bowl into the oven – water vapor will enhance heat
transfer and prevent drying out.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parbake for a few minutes. If the crust becomes brown, it’s been inside for too long – take it out immediately when it starts changing the colour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Hint: Parbaking may be considered cheating… but it allows you to make a perfect pizza without
a professional-grade oven. Also, if you made more dough, you can now freeze the pizza
and finish it off later, whenever you wish!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top with your favourite ingredients (most likely some tomato sauce and grated cheese).
Bake again for a few minutes until the crust is brown enough (but not burnt) and the cheese is melted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>english</category><category>recipes</category><guid>https://nix1.github.io/posts/easy-pizza-the-simplest-no-knead-home-made-pizza-ever/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 18:03:26 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>